- Hi and welcome to Ultimate
Go Programming LiveLessons.
My name is William Kennedy
and I am the author
of the, Go in Action, book
and the blog goinggo.net.
I also am the managing
partner of Ardan Labs
and Ardan Studios where we work
on Go projects all the time.
This video class is based
on the physical classes
that I teach week in and week
out throughout the world.
I do a lot of free classes on weekends
but we do a lot of corporate
three and four day classes,
and I finally felt now is the time that
this material was in a particular place
where I could deliver to you over video,
and this is where we're at now.
And I really hope you enjoy this course.
And really, at the end what
I want is that you can love
and appreciate Go as much as I do.
I have taken four years of
writing and thinking about Go
and been able to put it
together in this class.
So in this class,
what we're gonna be
covering is three things.
It's three things that I
think are incredibly important
to learning anything.
History, mechanics and then design.
So I'm gonna give you
a little bit of history
throughout this course
about where these idioms,
where these things are coming from.
Then I'm gonna be
sharing you the mechanics
of how things work inside and out,
and finally we get to talk about design,
and how to leverage
all of this information
to do things in a
productive and correct way.
So, from the language mechanics
we'll get into type and data structures.
We're gonna learn how this language works.
Then from a software design
we're gonna focus on decoupling
and composition and error
handling and packaging
and how we can think about architecturing
and designing software.
And finally of course you're gonna
want that concurrency stuff,
Goroutines, data races,
channels, patterns,
ways to think about writing
multithreaded software in Go,
and once all that's done
and you have that strong foundation,
we'll talk about testing
and really cool things
around how you can profile that code,
but I always want us to be focusing on
optimizing for correctness first.
This is gonna be a very big
theme throughout this class.
So I am so excited that I
finally get to share this class
almost in its entirety with you,
and you don't have to
worry about not being able
to have that corporate
classroom environment.
I've tried to deliver
that corporate classroom
environment to you.
So, hopefully now you're ready to go.
Sit down, get that drink,
get as excited as I am about this class,
and hopefully at the end of
the day you see the beauty
that this programming
language, Go, really has.